<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
 This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site.
 It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content.
 You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another.
 This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site.

 To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps:
 1. Log in to that site as an administrator.
 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel.
 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list.
 4. Activate & Run Importer.
 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page.
 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users
    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an
    existing user on the site or to create a new user.
 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc.
    contained in this file into your site.
-->
<!-- generator="WordPress.com" created="2023-02-05 21:23"-->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/">
  <channel>
<title>Yiling Huo academic</title>
<link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com</link>
<description/>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 21:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
<language>en</language>
<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
<wp:base_site_url>http://wordpress.com/</wp:base_site_url>
<wp:base_blog_url>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com</wp:base_blog_url>
<wp:author>
  <wp:author_id>182292504</wp:author_id>
  <wp:author_login>balalahelo</wp:author_login>
  <wp:author_email>huo.yiling.96@gmail.com</wp:author_email>
  <wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Huo Yiling]]></wp:author_display_name>
  <wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[YL]]></wp:author_first_name>
  <wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Huo]]></wp:author_last_name>
</wp:author>
<wp:term>
  <wp:term_id>132565</wp:term_id>
  <wp:term_taxonomy>nav_menu</wp:term_taxonomy>
  <wp:term_slug>my-work-social-network</wp:term_slug>
  <wp:term_name><![CDATA[My Work Social network]]></wp:term_name>
</wp:term>
<wp:term>
  <wp:term_id>132566</wp:term_id>
  <wp:term_taxonomy>nav_menu</wp:term_taxonomy>
  <wp:term_slug>page-directions</wp:term_slug>
  <wp:term_name><![CDATA[Page directions]]></wp:term_name>
</wp:term>
<wp:term>
  <wp:term_id>132564</wp:term_id>
  <wp:term_taxonomy>nav_menu</wp:term_taxonomy>
  <wp:term_slug>social</wp:term_slug>
  <wp:term_name><![CDATA[Social]]></wp:term_name>
</wp:term>
<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<image>
		<url>http://s0.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Yiling Huo academic</title>
		<link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<item>
  <title><![CDATA[10 Dec 2020]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/10/10-dec-2020/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 09:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=91</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph {"dropCap":true} -->
<p class="has-drop-cap">Today is the third week after I finished treatment. The PICC is still in my arm, so I still need to go to the hospital weekly to do its maintenance. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Many, many things have changed this year. I'm no longer the young, dreaming spirit. After my disease, moving back home, and the pandamic, now I'm just a young, dreaming spirit that have to care about realistic problems. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>My families have been so supportive. Sometimes, I get anxious of how supportive they are, knowing that there's nothing I can do to pay them back enough. But I guess I shouldn't let off these feelings on the people who care about me. I still need to really work on studentship applications, though, so that those feelings have a chance to go away forever. It seems that I've missed one of the studentships while in treatment, but according to my supervisor, my chances are slim, anyway. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>At the end of treatment I've made myself a goal of reading one paper a day, by today I've read about 20. Seems to me a good idea to write down some notes of them, so that they don't dissapear from my memory that easily. I wanted to have a wider knowledge of things that can help me in the future, so there was no limit in the subjects I'm reading.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The last two days I read Cogan et al. (2014) and Bouchard et al. (2013). It was the first time I've read electrocorticography (ECoG) studies. Although I knew about directly recording neural activity from the cortex, it was only when I read the article that I realised the direct recording electrodes aren't just put there during surgery, but they can stay on the cortex for quite a long time outside surgery too. This startled me a little bit, but then I thought of the tube that's in my own veins for half a year now, maybe it's not that surprising after all. It also surprised me a little how clean and clear ECoG data can be. My own thoughts aside, Cogan et al. (2014) sutdied sensory-motor transformations of speech, mainly using an overt word repetition task. They had 16 subjects having subdural electrodes on left, right, or both hamispheres. Apart from areas responding to auditory stimuli and areas responding to subject's speech, they identified sensory-motor responses bilaterally in the supramarginal gyrus, MTG, STG, somatosensory cortex, motor and premotor cortex, and IFG. They then used various methods to argue that the responses they found truly reflect sensory-motor transformation, and is specific to speech. At the end they argued that only the higher level processing of language is lateralized, while sensory-motor transformations are balancedly bilateral. Bouchard et al. (2016) used 3 subjects that have high-density multi-electrode arrays implated to study speech articulation. Recording neural activities during articulations of consonant-vowel syllables, they found spatially arranged representations of articulators (larynx, lips, jaw, tongue, then larynx again) on the vSMC. They argued that the second representation of larynx is specific to humans. They also found some temporal specificity for the vowels and consonants, as well as a hierarchical organization of phoneme representations that is arranged around usage of articulators. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Speaking of bilaterality, a few days ago I read Huth et al. (2016), an fMRI decoding/mapping study about sementic representations using voxel-wise analyses. Using data driven methods they identified 12 categories of words that are reprensented more or less separately in four data-driven dimensions. The 12 categories included tactile ('fingers'), visual ('yellow'), numeric ('four'), etc. They found that these patterns to be consistant across individuals (at least individuals from the same cultural backgroud) and occur highly bilateraly, relatively symmatrical, contradicting beliefs of left lateralized semantic representations, established from lesion studies. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There are many other articles I want to put down, but I'll stop here today.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Bouchard, K. E., Mesgarani, N., Johnson, K., &amp; Chang, E. F. (2013). Functional organization of human sensorimotor cortex for speech articulation.&nbsp;<em>Nature</em>,&nbsp;<em>495</em>(7441), 327-332.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Cogan, G. B., Thesen, T., Carlson, C., Doyle, W., Devinsky, O., &amp; Pesaran, B. (2014). Sensory–motor transformations for speech occur bilaterally.&nbsp;<em>Nature</em>,&nbsp;<em>507</em>(7490), 94-98.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Huth, A. G., De Heer, W. A., Griffiths, T. L., Theunissen, F. E., &amp; Gallant, J. L. (2016). Natural speech reveals the semantic maps that tile human cerebral cortex.&nbsp;<em>Nature</em>,&nbsp;<em>532</em>(7600), 453-458.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>91</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-10 17:16:30</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-10 09:16:30</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-10 17:26:14</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-10 09:26:14</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>10-dec-2020</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52052911121]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1607591795]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[11 Dec 2020, Emmendorfer et al. (2020)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/11/11-dec-2020-emmendorfer-et-al-2020/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 08:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/11/11-dec-2020-emmendorfer-et-al-2020/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is passive EEG oddball study investigating modulations of the MMN by phonotactic probability and stress. Language used was Dutch.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"left"} -->
<p class="has-text-align-left">From introduction I learned several things about predictions in speech. The authors used a distinction of formal and temporal predictions, and further described phonotactic mismatch as formal and stress as temporal. The authors explained that stress mismatch is similar to interrupting the meter of a beat, and therefore temporal.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Concerning predictions by phonotactic probability, I learned that while processing speed and accuracy are increased by higher probability, word learning is actually slowed by high phonotactic probabilities. This is explained by the hypothesis that low probability words are more easily identified as an object to learn. (References given: Strokel, 2009, Strokel &amp; Lee, 2011; Strokel et al. 2006). </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In addition, higher phonotactic probability is associated with higher amplitude of the MMN, supposedly representing facilitated processes.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In languages with fixed stress patterns (Hungarian, Finnish, where stress is always on the first syllable in bisyllabic words), deviant stress patterns elicit two consecutive MMNs, hypothesized to represent first the missing stress on the first syllable, then the added stress on the second syllable. (References: Honbolygó et al., 2004; Honbolygó &amp; Csépe, 2013; Ylinen et al., 2009).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This study manipulated phonotactic mismatch and stress mismatch at the same time. Participants listened to continuous repetitions of a Dutch pseudoword, with either formal oddballs or temporal oddballs. The authors found that oddballs of higher phonotactic probability gave an earlier latency of the MMN (note that they found differences in latency rather than amplitude), and stress did not appear to have impact on the MMN, amplitude or latency.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors explained the latency vs. amplitude issue saying that both higher amplitude and earlier latency reflect facilitated process, so their results are consistent with previous studies.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Emmendorfer, A. K., Correia, J. M., Jansma, B. M., Kotz, S. A., &amp; Bonte, M. (2020). ERP mismatch response to phonological and temporal regularities in speech. <em>Scientific reports</em>, <em>10</em>(1), 1-12.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Honbolygó, F., Csépe, V., &amp; Ragó, A. (2004). Suprasegmental speech cues are automatically processed by the human brain: a mismatch negativity study. <em>Neuroscience Letters</em>, <em>363</em>(1), 84-88.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Honbolygó, F., &amp; Csépe, V. (2013). Saliency or template? ERP evidence for long-term representation of word stress. <em>International journal of psychophysiology</em>, <em>87</em>(2), 165-172.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Storkel, H. L. (2009). Developmental differences in the effects of phonological, lexical, and semantic variables on word learning by infants. <em>Journal of child language</em>, <em>36</em>(2), 291.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Storkel, H. L., &amp; Lee, S. Y. (2011). The independent effects of phonotactic probability and neighbourhood density on lexical acquisition by preschool children. <em>Language and Cognitive Processes</em>, <em>26</em>(2), 191-211.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Storkel, H. L., Armbrüster, J., &amp; Hogan, T. P. (2006). Differentiating phonotactic probability and neighborhood density in adult word learning. <em>Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research</em>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Ylinen, S., Strelnikov, K., Huotilainen, M., &amp; Näätänen, R. (2009). Effects of prosodic familiarity on the automatic processing of words in the human brain. <em>International Journal of Psychophysiology</em>, <em>73</em>(3), 362-368.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>138</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-11 16:03:47</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-11 08:03:47</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-11 16:12:58</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-11 08:12:58</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>11-dec-2020-emmendorfer-et-al-2020</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="eeg"><![CDATA[EEG]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="mmn"><![CDATA[MMN]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="oddball-paradigm"><![CDATA[oddball paradigm]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="phonology"><![CDATA[phonology]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="prediction"><![CDATA[prediction]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1607673843]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52091199214]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[12 Dec 2020, Goucha, Zaccarella, &amp; Friederici (2017)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/12/12-dec-2020-goucha-zaccarella-friederici-2017/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 13:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/12/12-dec-2020-goucha-zaccarella-friederici-2017/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is a review that integrated theoretical linguistics, neuroscience of language, and evolutionary evidence in establishing that the arcuate fascicle is vital and human unique in labeling of word combinations. In doing so they also reviewed the locus and function of the language circuit in the brain. A very Max Planck article that’s nicely written. (This paper can also work as an index of brain anatomy of language, with roles of cortices and pathways concisely explained :), together with the ontogeny one.)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors first argued a little against the merge-only view of syntax saying that labeling (assigning heads, an + apple = DP{an apple} in stead of an + apple = {an apple} with labels assigned later at interfaces) is crucial to the computation of syntax. They argued that merge-only seems not able to explain hierarchical structure of language.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors then moved on to talk about the brain language circuit, with an emphasize on the white matter connections. They used empirical data as examples to show the role of BA44 in hierarchical syntax, frontal operculum in linear grammar, BA45 in combination process, as well as two dorsal pathways, the superior longitudinal fascicle connecting the STG/MTG with premotor cortex (responsible for auditory motor integration), and the arcuate fascicle connecting BA44 with posterior STG/MTG (syntactic complex structure processing). And two ventral pathways, the extreme fiber capsule system, including the inferior frontal-occipital fascicle (IFOF) connecting BA45/47 with the temporal cortex, the uncinate fascicle connecting ventral prefrontal cortex with ATL (these are said to be evolutionarily older).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The article then cited various empirical studies and reasoned that, in a word, the arcuate fascicle (together with the larger and more lateralized BA44) is crucial to the evolution of human language, enabling asymmetrical hierarchical structure building. They also encouraged future studies to look at the precise role of the arcuate fascicle in hierarchical structure building.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reference </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Goucha, T., Zaccarella, E., &amp; Friederici, A. D. (2017). A revival of Homo loquens as a builder of labeled structures: Neurocognitive considerations. <em>Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews</em>, <em>81</em>, 213-224.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>141</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-12 21:20:39</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-12 13:20:39</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-12 21:26:58</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-12 13:26:58</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>12-dec-2020-goucha-zaccarella-friederici-2017</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="arcuate-fascicle"><![CDATA[arcuate fascicle]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="language-faculty"><![CDATA[language faculty]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="max-planck"><![CDATA[Max Planck]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="review"><![CDATA[review]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1607779252]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52139148677]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[14 Dec 2020, Dautriche et al. (2015)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/14/14-dec-2020-dautriche-et-al-2015/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 13:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/14/14-dec-2020-dautriche-et-al-2015/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is a study from ENS Paris investigating novel word learning in 18-month-old French toddlers. It was shown in previous studies (Swingley &amp; Aslin, 2002, 2007) that toddlers have difficulties picking up novel nouns that sound like nouns they know (tog vs. dog), failing to recognize the word as a novel word to be learned because of the phonological similarity. In this study, they tested whether novel nouns that are similar to existing verbs are also difficult for children or as easy as novel words with no similarities.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>3 groups of 18-months-olds participated in the study. The authors did 3 experiments, each with different participants, testing noun-familiar words vs. no-familiar words, verb-familiar words vs. no-familiar words, and noun-familiar words vs. verb-familiar words. I suspect they did it this way rather than putting everything in one experiment is that they didn’t want to (or couldn’t) use more than two novel words in a single testing. Words used were as follows: noun: pallon (ballon), ganard (canard), gochon (cochon), pateau (bateau); verb: barti (parti), dombé (tombé), gassé (cassé), tonné (donné); no: prolin, barlié, torba, lagui. Teaching phase was some teaching videos, testing phase used language guided looking paradigm (“Regarde le [], tu le vois le []?”).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>3 experiments together showed that proportion of look to target was always on chance level for the noun condition, while quickly increased at about 600ms after target word onset for both verb condition and no-familiar condition, similar to the results using well known real words (as baseline). </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors concluded that although what exactly guided the learning of verb-familiar novel words (the fact that novel and familiar words are from different syntactic categories, syntax; or the fact that they represent object vs. movement, semantics), it is clear that toddlers did not rely solely on phonology to determine which word is a novel word that should be learned.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The experiments and data seems very clean and convincing (although I noticed that they had to throw away almost 1/3 of the participants, such are children I guess :)). However I couldn’t help but ask some questions.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In their design, it seems that they carefully matched the gender of the novel words and their familiar noun (le ganard vs. le canard), this is not entirely unimportant because the testing guidance used the article le/la “Regarde le []”, and they didn’t specify whether the definite article or indefinite article was used in the teaching phase. I think it would be interesting to test whether novel words are still difficult to learn if the syntactic gender was changed (la ganard vs. le canard). This little change might also help the authors to ascertain the “syntax or semantics helps” issue mentioned in their discussion.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Another small thing brought up by the articles was about the verb condition. In discussion the authors admitted that children may not think of the verb that is similar to the novel word they are hearing in the teaching videos, due to the very different context nouns and verbs appear, this also raises the question of whether children were affected by n-gram probability (what is n-gram called in the more linguistic context again?).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Also, I wonder if it would be interesting to test some novel nouns similar to verbs *only when including their article* (le vée vs. lever) (maybe not so much) (but again the authors used words that are differentiable on the first consonant so that’s a little tricky).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Dautriche, I., Swingley, D., &amp; Christophe, A. (2015). Learning novel phonological neighbors: Syntactic category matters. <em>Cognition</em>, <em>143</em>, 77-86.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Swingley, D., &amp; Aslin, R. N. (2002). Lexical neighborhoods and the word-form representations of 14-month-olds. <em>Psychological science</em>, <em>13</em>(5), 480-484.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Swingley, D., &amp; Aslin, R. N. (2007). Lexical competition in young children’s word learning. <em>Cognitive psychology</em>, <em>54</em>(2), 99-132.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>150</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-14 21:34:40</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-14 13:34:40</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-14 21:41:03</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-14 13:41:03</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>14-dec-2020-dautriche-et-al-2015</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="eye-tracking"><![CDATA[eye-tracking]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="french"><![CDATA[French]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="language-development"><![CDATA[language development]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="word-learning"><![CDATA[word learning]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1607952895]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52213600876]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[15 Dec 2020, Zaccarella et al. (2017)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/15/15-dec-2020-zaccarella-et-al-2017/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 07:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/15/15-dec-2020-zaccarella-et-al-2017/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is an fMRI study that clearly served as one of the bases for Goucha, Zaccarella, &amp; Friederici (2017). The study looked at the syntactic computation merge, and tried to identify its neural basis.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The study compared 3-word sentences vs. preposition phrases vs. noun lists, and found that sentences + phrases - noun list showed activation in the IFG peaking at BA44, and in the pSTS. Moreover, sentences - noun lists showed a peak in BA44, while phrases - noun lists showed a peak in BA45. In consideration of previous studies, the authors concluded that BA44 may be responsible for structure building, BA45 for encoding of propositional meaning initiated by the verb, and pSTS for thematic role assignment.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Stimuli were 3-word sentences (with verb, “the ship sinks”), phrases (PP without verb “on the ship”), and noun lists (“ship stem juice”). The authors chose noun list instead of lists of both nouns and function words because they believed lists including function words may elicit additional syntax processing. Participants saw one word at a time for 300ms, and were asked to push a button to indicate whether what they just saw was a sentence/phrase, a word list, or rubbish (rubbish?).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Later in discussions, the authors address the doubt that the differences in brain activation may only reflect processing of function words since the word list condition didn’t have any. They suggested that previous studies using all-function-word list as control also found activation of BA44 in sentence - word list (Maguire and Firth, 2004).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors stressed that the activation in BA44 in both sentence and phrase conditions could mean that BA44 is involved even in the minimal structure building. So I wonder if it would be interesting to test this using Chinese, where we can omit the article in “the ship sinks” and “on the ship”, and two words can already form very meaningful structures such as “吃饭”. I seem to remember that some study have already done this (might want to look later), which would be a very good complement to this study.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One question the authors left for future studies is whether BA44’s structure building is language specific or domain general, since recent evidence suggests involvement of BA44 in music and mathematics, etc.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>(One small personal thought: I’m always a little bit skeptical of this kind of fMRI studies looking at very fine grained structures in language, simply because the poor temporal resolution of fMRI. One question seems to be always there: no matter how carefully we design the study, can we be 100% sure the BOLD differences IS elicited by what we are testing, not by whatever other differences there might be in the stimuli? But I see the effort of researchers trying very hard to address this issue, and I appreciate it.)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Maguire EA, Frith CD. The brain network associated with acquiring semantic knowledge. <em>Neuroimage</em>. 2004 May;22(1):171-8. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2003.12.036. PMID: 15110007.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Zaccarella, E., Meyer, L., Makuuchi, M., &amp; Friederici, A. D. (2017). Building by syntax: the neural basis of minimal linguistic structures. <em>Cerebral Cortex</em>, <em>27</em>(1), 411-421.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>154</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-15 15:44:44</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-15 07:44:44</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-15 15:59:48</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-15 07:59:48</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>15-dec-2020-zaccarella-et-al-2017</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="ba44"><![CDATA[BA44]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="fmri"><![CDATA[fMRI]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="max-planck"><![CDATA[Max Planck]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="merge"><![CDATA[merge]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="minimal-structure"><![CDATA[minimal structure]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1608018300]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52243836347]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[17 Dec 2020, Coderre et al. (2020), and thoughts]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/17/17-dec-2020-coderre-et-al-2020-and-thoughts/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 12:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/17/17-dec-2020-coderre-et-al-2020-and-thoughts/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The paper was actually read yesterday, but yesterday I felt there weren’t much to talk about alongside. Today was hospital day, I did my PET scan. Funny enough, I’ve now been inside PET scanners more times than MRI scanners. This was my third PET, and I finally googled the question I’ve always wondered about, why do they ask us to drink milk before the scan? I first searched in English and found nothing, then Japanese and also nothing. I finally googled in Chinese (sorry GFW), and found the disappointing answer that they just needed something inside our stomach to get a better stomach image. It actually didn’t matter at all whether it’s milk or water or anything. It feels funny now thinking about how my mom always put so much effort to make me fresh sugar free soy milk the night before, because of my lactose intolerance . I guess the reason why I found nothing in the first two searches was other countries may not specify the milk part. I also guess the reason why we especially asked patients to drink milk instead of any other liquid is that milk is probably one of the least likely drinks to contain sugar? During my search I found images explaining how blood sugar level massively affects PET scan quality, which is very interesting.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Back to the paper. This is a very familiar predictability N400 study. Every single thing is done the typical N400 way, cloze task, high predictably vs. low vs. anomalous, 8 electrodes, ISI 350, etc., except that the authors used comics instead of sentences to test non verbal prediction effects.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The results are typically N400, too. The anomalous pictures evokes a higher amplitude N400, 400-800ms fronto-central. They also found the N400 to be more negative 500-600ms in low cloze vs. high cloze central, although the effect was tiny. They also correlated cloze probability with N400 amplitude, and found significances.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors also noted that the N400 in this study is slightly later than typical, which they attributed to the visual complexity of comic images. In sum, they concluded that the N400 component is sensor to visual narrative they same way it is to linguistic narrative. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Coderre, E. L., O’Donnell, E., O’Rourke, E., &amp; Cohn, N. (2020). Predictability modulates neurocognitive semantic processing of non-verbal narratives. <em>Scientific reports</em>, <em>10</em>(1), 1-11.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>157</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-17 20:01:35</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-17 12:01:35</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-17 20:05:22</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-17 12:05:22</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>17-dec-2020-coderre-et-al-2020-and-thoughts</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="eeg"><![CDATA[EEG]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="visual-narrative"><![CDATA[visual narrative]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1608206507]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52334738091]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[19 Dec 2020, Fengler, Meyer, &amp; Friederici (2016)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/19/19-dec-2020-fengler-meyer-friederici-2016/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 08:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/19/19-dec-2020-fengler-meyer-friederici-2016/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>An fMRI study from Max Planck looking at developmental attunement of the brain (PO &amp; IPL/pSTG) to functional selective language processing.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>3 age groups were tested: 5-6 years, 7-8 years, and adults, using sentences with no embedded clause (baseline), one embedded clause (simple syntax), and two embedded clauses (complex syntax) (the complex syntax was so complex that I read the example 10 times and still didn’t understand the meaning. But hey, it’s German). Task was to find the correct picture from two pictures that represents the sentence.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Some of the results are as follows:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Behaviorally, only 5-6 years showed different reaction time for simple vs. complex.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Whole brain, interaction of complexity x age in left PO, left IPL to pSTG, bilateral cerebellum, and supplementary motor area. (I later discovered that they meant bilateral cerebellum AND BILATERAL supplementary motor.)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>ROIs were mainly left Pars Opercularis, left IPL/pSTG (word “left” omitted below). Brain functional complexity score (selectivity) increased with age (but not between two children groups) for all ROIs and SMA and cerebellum. Gray matter probability decreased with age (also not between children) in PO and IPL/pSTG. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Accuracy negatively associated with activation in the ROIs. Brain functional complexity scores correlated with digit span, representing positive correlation if sun too la selectivity with visual working memory.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Regressions. Structure coefficients are used (correlations coefficients not influenced by other predictors (?)). GMP and digit span explained most variance in Brain functional complexity score in both ROIs. Commonality analysis, brain functional complexity score best explained by shared variance of age and GMP; age, GMP, and digit span; age and digit span in IPL/pSTG. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Group specific regressions. In 5-6 years, activation difference in PO between complex and simple predicted by activation in the SMA. In 7-8 years predicted partially by SMA. In adults, fully predicted by IPL/pSTG. (Stepwise attunement).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors discussed the results as finding a well-described network in left hemisphere for adults, and a functional attunement toward adult-like selectivity for complex sentences across development. In PO, only adults show selectivity, and establishment of adult like selectivity is predicted by PO’s GMP across age groups. GMP reduction in left IPL/pSTG is also associated with attunement toward adult activity patterns.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors concluded that structural brain maturation and visual working memory expansion provide basis for functional selectivity in language areas.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reference</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Fengler A, Meyer L, Friederici AD. How the brain attunes to sentence processing: Relating behavior, structure, and function. <em>Neuroimage</em>. 2016 Apr 1;129:268-278. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2016.01.012. Epub 2016 Jan 15. PMID: 26777477; PMCID: PMC4819595.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>162</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-19 16:48:49</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-19 08:48:49</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-19 16:48:49</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-19 08:48:49</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>19-dec-2020-fengler-meyer-friederici-2016</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="brain-maturation"><![CDATA[brain maturation]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="fmri"><![CDATA[fMRI]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="functional-selectivity"><![CDATA[functional selectivity]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="max-planck"><![CDATA[Max Planck]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1608367740]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52409149467]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[21 Dec 2020, revision]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/21/21-dec-2020-revision/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 04:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=163</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>(The following words contain many omitted hyphens, commas, parentheses, etc. :p)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Today seems good to revise what I’ve read in this little project. I started off just searching some language and neuro related key words, then collected any articles whose title sounded interesting. Many of the papers are from Nature’s Scientific Report, which has many good open access articles. I also kept in mind to mostly include recent papers. As of today I’ve gone through 26 papers. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I can put these articles into 5 categories, language representation in brain, formal syntax in brain, acquisition, processing of language (the ERPs not the NLPs), and finally the nice little knowledge from other fields category. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The first category mostly includes (f)MRI studies, and the two ECoG studies about speech in sensory-motor cortex. I’m unfamiliar with ECoG, but I was astonished that this method is able to obtain very clean data from just a few patients with different arrangements of electrodes. The two studies, in a word, told me that articulation in sensory-motor is hierarchical, which is not unlike the categorization of phones in phonetics; and that speech sensory-motor transformation may be specific, and happens bilaterally. I wonder if it’s because the two papers I happened to read were both about speech, or it’s that speech is a popular language topic in ECoG. If more ECoG studies were about speech, maybe it’s because sensory-motor cortex is very important in epilepsy surgery? (so more patients with electrodes on that area)?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Other than the two studies, the (f)MRI studies are mostly about semantic representation, lateralization, and development/plasticity. One of the semantic papers was a review (Patterson et al., 2007) combining fMRI and patient studies (semantic dementia). Except for the familiar fMRI based language network, disorder studies showed involvement of the bilateral ATL in semantic representations, maybe serving as the semantic hub handling cross- model task-dependent representations. Also proposing bilateral semantic representation is Huth et al., 2016 using fMRI decoding to establish an atlas of semantic representations, which is widely distributed (temporal, parietal, and prefrontal), symmetrically bilateral, and consistent across individuals. These results lead to the thinking of language lateralization may be more “language specific”, that brain activities within the “meaning” part of language (in my view the integration of word with emm.. memory?) may be highly bilateral. Two of the other studies talked about language lateralization and handedness, one is a meta analysis (sort of) that found no direct associations between language lateralization and handedness; one is an fMRI study that showed left-handed trilinguals’ third language may have different lateralization than the other two, no more differences was found in the right-handed group. Overall these two studies indicated weak or even non-existing associations between handedness and language lateralization. (Yazbek et al 2020, Packheiser et al 2020)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One of the developmental fMRI studies I read compared neonates and adults’ VWFA, and found that the VWFA already looks language selective at birth and are more functionally connected to language areas (Li et al 2020). Another is a DTI study talking about bilingualism and the left AF &amp; IFOF (Mohades et al 2015). They found that bilingualism and AOA of L2 affects maturation and myelination of those connections. Similarly talking about parameters of brain development, Dehaene et al 2010 compared literates and illiterates’ VWFA, and found that literacy, acquired early or late, enhances VWFA’s response to scripts, allows the entire language network to be activated by written language, and also refined phonological processing. But there were competition effects in the VWFA too, resulting in its reduced response to faces and checkerboards. Finally, Barnes-Davis et al 2020 studies extremely preterm children’s language areas and showed bilateral cortical thickness normalized by intracranial volume increased in EPT children. They suggested that an interhemispheric pathway involving cerebellum may be key to development of language in EPT children. (Does this mean they are also suggesting language lateralization associated with preterm-ness? (← what is this word))</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second category is three papers from Max Planck Germany that studied the neural basis for minimal sentence structure. Goucha Zaccarella Friederici 2017 is a good summarize of these studies.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>On acquisition, an empirical study and a review I read stressed the importance of both language specific learning mechanisms (e.g. tested by artificial grammar learning) and statistical learning. (Dautriche et al 2015, Gómez and Gerken 2000). There were also two similar studies on artificial L2 that showed the advantage of learning from chunks (gendered article + noun) benefits learning of syntactic gender.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The ERP studies mainly added to my previous knowledge, and the following summarization may sound very fragmental. Calma &amp; Drury 2020, the N400 is sensitive to music patterns as well as language; Coderre et al 2020, the N400 sensitive to visual narratives (comics); Emmendorfer et al 2020, the MMN sensitive to predictability (more predictable oddballs make greater MMN) but not to stress.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Because the way I’ve chosen the papers (randomly), it feels very difficult to put them together in one summary. And when I do it feels like bullet points without the bullet points. But a terrible summary is nonetheless better than no summary. My next step, I’ve marked some interesting papers in the references of the papers I’m reading, and hopefully later I’ll have more things to talk about on specific topics, and the next summaries will hopefully be topic-wise.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/my-blog/reading-list/" target="_blank">My reading list</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>163</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-21 12:03:14</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-21 04:03:14</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-21 17:20:18</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-21 09:20:18</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>21-dec-2020-revision</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1608542295]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52482204158]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[26 Dec 2020, Science no. 6461]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/27/26-dec-2020-science-no-6461/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 14:39:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=170</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The power of the internet let me found a physical copy of Science issue 6461, the Language and the Brain special issue. It features four reviews that summarizes neural basis of human language from different views: evolution, comprehension/processing, speech perception and production, and combinatory syntax vs. semantics. It’s actually the first time I’ve read scientific journals in its “magazine”form. It feels so unrealistic seeing scientific reports printed together with so many ads just like fashion magazines. I’ve also realized I’ve been assuming that many journals now only publish in digital form (meaning the things that pop up on google scholar are everything there are to a journal), but I can be massively wrong!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The evolution review (Erich Jarvis 2019) focused on vocal learning and speech, and compared those neural networks in humans, songbirds, vocal birds (one can learn new songs and one can only sing instinctively), and primates. Because I was so unfamiliar with the subject (at least in English), it took the full set of my comprehension skills and my contextual vocabulary learning skills to read the paper. It’s very interesting to see some more biological terms like “forebrain” being used to describe human language systems. This review, in one word, argues that the neural basis of speech learning is more shared among species than previously thought, though challenging a little the notion of the uniqueness of human language.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The processing review is by Peter Hagoort. the author started from the classical Broca + Wernicke model of language in the brain, and extended on a few different levels why the classical model is not accurate. On neuroplasticity, the author review studies on the congenitally blind population, and pointed out selective recruitment of the visual cortex in language in this population. The author then followed a “step of processing” line of reasoning, and reviewed the immediacy principle (information processed immediately rather than wait for whole structure), where the author then linked to the role of prediction, and how the LIFC and temporoparietal areas dynamically work during the immediate processing of information and prediction. This is also where I’ll start from in my PhD. Next, the author reviewed how some paralinguistics features like topic and pragmatic inference  gare processed. Two things I’ve learned are that the N400 and the P600 were more robust when the unexpected word is part of the focus constituent; and that some pragmatic processing (such as understanding indirect requests) are found to activate the theory of mind network in the right temporoparietal junction and medial prefrontal cortex. The author ended the review proposing a multiple network view of language processing.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The third review is by Sophie Scott on speech and social interaction in the brain. This review also compared human speech to sounds in animals, and continued to summarize some important studies on speech recognition, adaptation (to accents and to noise), speech in imagery. The author continued to talk about the role of the STG and auditory representations, citing evidences of representation of syllables (rather than individual phonemes). The review then transited to include the overlapping of speech networks and other modalities, then moving forward to speech and social communication.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The last review is the one I’m most interested in, by Liina Pylkkänen on the neural basis of combinatory syntax and semantics. The most interesting about this paper is that it stated the idea that maybe the brain doesn’t build syntax structure during language processing. The review started from MEG studies looking for syntax in brain (using minimal syntax structure vs. word lists), and stressed the role of ventral medial prefrontal cortex and left ATL. But then the review cited further studies that found that maybe both the vmPFC and lATL are not doing purely syntactic work but combinatory semantics work (evidence from differences of activation in these regions when semantic range changes but syntax stays the same eg. “Korean food” vs. “Asian food”). The reason to doubt a purely syntax process in the brain were made with four points according to the author: (1) neural signals are dominated by meaning not syntax during natural language processing (no not THAT NLP haha). (2) Although several regions are reliably linked to syntax, we don’t know to what degree the activation is driven by syntax per se or combinatory semantics (does combinatory<strong> </strong>semantics here mean what the syntax semantics interface mean in theoreticals?). (3) Electrophysiological signal rythmically tracks syntactic phrases, but the question is still open whether the tracking is about syntax or combinatory semantics. (But the author then said studies using artificial grammar replicated this rythmic tracking so this may be more syntax than semantics.)   There was a nice picture summarizing roles of lATL and vmPFC in combinatory efforts vs. AG and PTL and LIFG which are more purely syntax (argument structure, syntax combinations, long distance dependencies, respectively). A brief timeframe is also there on the image. In the concluding remarks, the author proposed that syntax may be something the brain knows rather than does, meaning that syntactic processing amounts to comparing semantic structures to stored knowledge of syntax. The author did admit the role of syntax in prediction later, though, saying that syntax may have a role in top-down predictive processing, but the bottom-up processing may be pure semantic.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Half way through this paper I had many questions, but in the end I felt this paper doesn’t contradict with anything I previously know, after all. First of all, studies in this article did use the minimal of minimal structures (something like “blue boat” not even with a “the”), which is quite different even with those fMRI studies I’ve read using minimal structures (at least full sentences like “the dog eats”). It feels natural that the “blue boats” are largely semantic. Then, the idea of syntax being more top-down and semantics dominate the bottom-up seems somehow natural to me, though being a freshperson like myself I cannot immediately cite tons of papers supporting this idea. I guess at the end of the day it’s about what we mean by “processing”, the author of this article apparently is referring to the “earlier” steps (earlier in quotes because some of the semantic combination effects are observed 300-400ms) of understanding the meaning, while I’m more familiar with “later” steps of what happens when the basic meaning is already available.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>(Just one little complain here when nobody is reading, can we think of a better term than “processing”??? It’s really awkward when people just naturally thinks it’s the NLP! Or should I be happy that the human brain and the computers are so alike now that we’ve started to use colliding terms?)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hagoort, P. (2019). The neurobiology of language beyond single-word processing. <em>Science</em>, <em>366</em>(6461), 55-58.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Jarvis, E. D. (2019). Evolution of vocal learning and spoken language. <em>Science</em>, <em>366</em>(6461), 50-54.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Pylkkänen, L. (2019). The neural basis of combinatory syntax and semantics. <em>Science</em>, <em>366</em>(6461), 62-66.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Scott, S. K. (2019). From speech and talkers to the social world: The neural processing of human spoken language. <em>Science</em>, <em>366</em>(6461), 58-62.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>170</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-27 22:39:05</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-27 14:39:05</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-31 20:51:09</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-31 12:51:09</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>26-dec-2020-science-no-6461</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="evolution"><![CDATA[evolution]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="processing"><![CDATA[processing]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="review"><![CDATA[review]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="science"><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="speech"><![CDATA[speech]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="syntax"><![CDATA[syntax]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1609079814]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52708434503]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_old_date</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2020-12-26]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[28 Dec 2020, Crinion et al. (2006)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/28/28-dec-2020-crinion-et-al-2006/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 07:58:53 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/28/28-dec-2020-crinion-et-al-2006/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A PET+fMRI study on language control in the bilingual brain. The study used a two-word priming paradigm, in a 2-by-2-by-2 design, they manipulated semantic relatedness (trout-SALMON vs. trout-HORSE), same vs. different language (trout-SALMON vs. trout-LACHS), and target language (trout-LACHS vs. forelle-SALMON).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One group of German-English bilinguals participated in the PET study, and a group of German-English bilinguals + a group of Japanese-English bilinguals participated in the fMRI study. Participants viewed successively presented word pairs and were asked to make a lexical decision based on the second word. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The ventral surface of the lATL as well as behavioral showed a main effect of relatedness, but no effects of language, suggesting language-independent priming effects.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The left caudate, however, showed many language-dependent effects. Related words reduced activation in the left caudate when the word pair is in the same language more than when in different languages, irrespective of the language of the prime/target. The authors argued that the results reflect language control, rather than orthographic effects, because otherwise the same vs. different language would lead to activation differences irrespective of semantic relatedness, which was not the case.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors proposed two possible mechanisms underlying their findings: that different languages are processing using different populations of neurons, and priming only affected neurons for the prime language, thus not reducing activation when processing other languages; or that the same neurons respond to semantic input in both languages with increased neuronal firing when there is a change in language. The authors favored the second explanation, citing lesion studies for evidence.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A lesion study cited reported a trilingual patient with lesion to white matters surrounding the head of the left caudate, who showed no difficulty in comprehension in all three languages, but showed involuntary language switch in production (Abutalebi et al 2000), thus supporting the role of left caudate in language control (rather than each area processes one language, which, come to think about it, is a cute idea that kinda show characteristics of 2006 papers).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors also cited several lesion studies in monolingual patients, suggesting similar role of left caudate in lexical control.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Finally, the authors stressed anatomical connections with the left caudate receiving projections from frontal, temporal, and parietal association regions in language-dominant hemisphere, and sending projections via the thalamus which play a role in motor planning of articulation.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Abutalebi, J., Miozzo, A., &amp; Cappa, S. F. (2000). Do subcortical structures control ‘language selection’in polyglots? Evidence from pathological language mixing. <em>Neurocase</em>, <em>6</em>(1), 51-56.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Crinion, J., Turner, R., Grogan, A., Hanakawa, T., Noppeney, U., Devlin, J. T., ... &amp; Usui, K. (2006). Language control in the bilingual brain. <em>Science</em>, <em>312</em>(5779), 1537-1540.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>179</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-28 15:58:53</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-28 07:58:53</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-31 20:48:22</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-31 12:48:22</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>28-dec-2020-crinion-et-al-2006</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="bilingualism"><![CDATA[bilingualism]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="fmri"><![CDATA[fMRI]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="language-control"><![CDATA[language control]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="left-caudate"><![CDATA[left caudate]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="lexical-priming"><![CDATA[lexical priming]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="pet"><![CDATA[PET]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="science"><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52733784663]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1609142354]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[30 Dec 2020, Bianchi et al. (2020)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/30/30-dec-2020-bianchi-et-al-2020/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 10:04:34 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/30/30-dec-2020-bianchi-et-al-2020/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is a study comparing cloze-probability with several NLP techniques (a N-gram model, Latent Semantic Analysis LSA, Word2Vec, FastText) in predicting eye movement (gaze duration).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>They used a N-gram + cache model (cache: train a additional N-gram model using the text read up to the present word to capture recent information). </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For the word embedding models, they used cosine similarity as the computer-predictability (the semantic distance between the actual word and the predicted word I guess). </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>They analyzed how each of the models explained eye-tracking data of Spanish short stories, focusing on gaze duration. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>They did analysis with predictability of the current word and the N+1 word. Besides cloze-probability, 4-gram + cache was the best performing model. The N-gram model also correlated with gaze duration in the same direction as cloze-predictability. The authors also argued that the word embedding models were likely to capture long-term effects (in long texts?).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I’m not sure that I fully understood what this paper is trying to say, but I’m glad to have some knowledge on NLP.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Bianchi, B., Monzón, G. B., Ferrer, L., Slezak, D. F., Shalom, D. E., &amp; Kamienkowski, J. E. (2020). Human and computer estimations of Predictability of words in written language. <em>Scientific reports</em>, <em>10</em>(1), 1-11.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>183</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-30 18:04:34</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-30 10:04:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-31 20:49:04</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-31 12:49:04</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>30-dec-2020-bianchi-et-al-2020</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="nlp"><![CDATA[NLP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="predictability"><![CDATA[predictability]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1609322684]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52814510526]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[31 Dec 2020, Dehaene et al. (2015)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/31/31-dec-2020-dehaene-et-al-2015/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 12:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=187</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A review on the effect of literacy on functions of brain systems. In this paper, the authors mainly included fMRI and ERP studies comparing literate, ex-illiterate (people who acquired reading as adults), and illiterate populations. (I must say that when reading this I've mistaken the words "literate" and "illiterate" too many times, the little i is easy to miss). (I'm omitting many references of empirical studies in the below notes, but future me can refer to the original paper for them since the paper is nicely organized it should be easy.)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>At the beginning and also at the end, the authors stressed that current methods are hard to dissociate literacy from schooling and socio-economic factors. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The review first looked at literacy's effect on early visual processing, starting from that literacy generally enhances responses of early visual cortices to various stimuli, as well as enhances a 140-180ms occipital ERP. In alphabetic readers, literacy enhances responses of V1 to horizontal checker-boards (In Chinese readers the same effects are seen in V3 and V4). These enhancements are explained by perceptual learning, target- and location-specific improvement in the identification of well-learnt stimuli. As a result, literate people may have better image analysis strategies.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The ventral visual pathway, especially the visual word form area VWFA, is shaped by literacy. Besides the well-known activation vs. no activation from scripts at the VWFA in literate vs. illiterate populations, the authors extended to a detailed description of the relations between VWFA's function and literacy. Reading speed is apparently related to VWFA activation. ERP also shows that the N170 (coming from the left ventral occipitotemporal cortex) is enhanced in literate people. Development of these effects takes place early and quickly, in 6-year-olds for a few weeks of training. In 9-year-olds the VWFA already shows strong selectivity of letters. In adults, a few days of training in a novel script also increase activation in the VWFA, though plasticity in adults may be weaker (activation of VWFA from face recognition doesn't seem to weaken in adults).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>"The VWFA is generally agreed to intervene in the efficient identification of orthographic stimuli and to enable quick association of such stimuli with phonological and lexical information." But the authors expressed that there's debate on how specialized the VWFA is for reading. One view is that the VWFA specializes in orthographic coding, the other view is that the VWFA has an abstract, non-orthographic code that also works for pictures. The authors identified the main issue here is not whether the VWFA has top-down influences (yes), but rather whether such top-down inputs are orthography specific. The authors favor the first view, citing a study that recorded ECoG signals while learning a new script, which found top-down effects at the VWFA site occur early with a few days of training, whereas bottom-up tuning occurs days later. The authors also noted that in congenitally blind populations, the VWFA also emerges when learning to read in Braille, suggesting the area to be meta-modal. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The emergence fo the VWFA affects face reccognition. the fusiform face area FFA becomes more right-lateralized as literacy increases, as early as the age of four. In adults, the sizes of responses to written words and facdes are inversely correlated. Anatomically, "a recently identifies cytoarchitectonic area, the human fusiform gyrus region known as 'FG2', seems to afford fMRI responses both to words and to faces and therefore may be the shared neuroanatomical resource for which both categories of stimuli compete". </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Literacy also affects mirror invariance, the ability to recognize a visual image as identical after left-right inversions. Mirror invariance, whose brain area overlaps with the VWFA, is stronger in illiterate people than literate, supported by both fMRI and EEG, though the authors suspected the effect may only present in people learning scripts that contain mirrored pairs (d-b, p-q). On the other hand, literate people are better at discriminate mirror pictures and symbols.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Literacy largely interacts with speech-processing. Generally, literacy increases activation by speech. Specifically, two regions, the planum temporale PT and the VWFA are most affected. The PT has representations of consonants and vowels of spoken language, attuned to the native language. Amplitude of PT activation is incresed with literacy (approximately two-folds). "The literacy-associated increase in PT activation may indicate a refinement of one or more types of phonological representation". Behaviorally, literacy increases explicit phonological knowledge, allowing literal people to perform better in tasks involving phoneme discrimination. The VWFA, in literates more than illiterates, also has top-down activation in listening tasks that require conversion from phonology to orthography. ERP suggects this effect occurs early, and could modulate core processes of lexical access. Literacy may also help develop verbal memory for spoken materials. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Anatomically, literacy modifies the posterior temporoparietal protion of the left arcuate fasciculus, which may participate in the development of the grapheme-to-phoneme conversion route; and thickens the splenium and/or the isthmus of the corpus callosum, which reflects enhanced interhemispheric tranfer of phonological and visual information. Literacy is also reported to increase grey matter density in several regions of the angular, supramarginal and temporal gyri, the bilateral dorsal occipitao-parietal region, bilateral middle temporal gyri, and superior temporal gyri. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>At the end, the authors expressed that studies can look at the effects of literacy on more general cognitive abilities. Literacy seems to have an impact on some complex working-memory tasks such as listening span, but so far, as the authors noted, the few studies on this topic haven't had good dissociation between literacy and schooling. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Dehaene, S., Cohen, L., Morais, J.&nbsp;<em>et al.</em>&nbsp;Illiterate to literate: behavioural and cerebral changes induced by reading acquisition.&nbsp;<em>Nat Rev Neurosci</em>&nbsp;<strong>16,&nbsp;</strong>234–244 (2015). https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn3924</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>187</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-31 20:02:10</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-31 12:02:10</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-31 20:49:40</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-31 12:49:40</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>31-dec-2020-dehaene-et-al-2015</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="literacy"><![CDATA[literacy]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="reading"><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="review"><![CDATA[review]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1609416135]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52856627826]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[31 Dec 2020, thoughts]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2020/12/31/31-dec-2020-thoughts/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 12:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=196</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is the last day of the year. I read a nicely organized paper today and wrote notes I feel longer than any notes I've written (on a single paper), so my rubbish has to be a new post. 2020 feels so strange. I've been through so many things yet memories are still fuzzy. Last year on this day, I was probably at my rented room in SH worring about my applications of scholarships. Today I'm at my home (though as I've been out of the home for long enough it feels more like 'mom's place') worring about my applications of scholarchips. Everything changed and nothing changed. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The end of year is when no TV shows have new episodes, but luckly all the illustrators I follow on SNS are posting a lot of stuff. Guess they're bored of no new TV, too. It certainly won't show on this blog, but I do have many dearest hobbies. Every year at this time I try to do a version of the illustrator's 'the year in a nutshell' challenge or whatever that's called in English, but with whatever I'm working on. I remember 2018's to be very colorful, with my undergrad thesis in French on formal syntax, some translation work I've done and was payed for, as well as course essays for UCL. I was always so happy to do so many different things. I feel like I'm change-liking person not because I enjoy change in my life (I'm terrified of it just like everyone else), but because when I sit back and look at my life, the periods when a lot of changes happen are also the ones I'll recall with a smile on my face. I also remember I didn't do the chanllenge in 2019, although it would feature my proud MSc thesis, mainly because I couldn't bring myself to randomly post anything about my work online. I also didn't do many meaningful writings during my work anyways. 2020 when I think about it, besides the things that happened in my personal life, on the productive side, there's still my work, the study I'm still doing with Dr. Chow, and there's this blog. So if I'm to post four pictures summarizing this year it might be a screenshot of the eyelink Data Viewer, my poster that I presented at CUNY, a page of this blog, and maybe my CV perhaps (I know but I really like how my CV is visually presented). During the time when I was too sick to study I've also done some creative writing, but let's not get into details here. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I feel like writing these summarizing words is also helping me develop some confidence, listing down all the things I've produced surely was very enjoyable.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I hope my 2021 summary can feature this blog, too, somethings form my PhD, and hopefully the study with Dr. Chow in it's manuscript form. (Also, help! I don't know when to switch from the respectful form to Wing-Yee, or whether I should switch at all, help! -from a clueless intercultural person)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I think that's about it. Happy New Year!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>196</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-12-31 20:39:54</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-12-31 12:39:54</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-12-31 20:39:54</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-12-31 12:39:54</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>31-dec-2020-thoughts</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52857666832]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1609418399]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[2 Jan 2021, Sun et al. (2020) &amp; Saito et al. (2020)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/02/2-jan-2021-sun-et-al-2020-saito-et-al-2020/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 05:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=209</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The two studies in which I was participant from last year? two years ago? Yesterday the experimenter notified us about them. The studies are about explicit &amp; implicit auditory processing in relation to adult L2 speech acquisition. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The first study used the frequency following response (FFR), an EEG response coming from subcortical areas that mirrors the frequency of auditory stimuli (and so differences of the FFR can be seen with different vowels). The FFR has consistant individual differences, and is being used to evaluate variability in implicit auditory processing abilities. The studies tested participant's sound discrimination threshold (explicit auditory processing) using a 3-tone dicision task. Thresholds of pitch, formant, duration, and amplitude were tested. Music memory (melody &amp; rythm) was tested using a repitition task with button presses. EEG responses was recorded as participants listened to a 170ms repitative syllable /da/ for 20 minutes. (I remembet the process was pure torture). From 5ms to 50ms F1, F2, F3 raised (transition from consonant to vowel?). Data of L2 experience (hours of usage) and musical experience (yes or no), as well as L2 speech perception proficiency (minimal consonant and stress distcrimination) were also collected. Being a longitudinal study, the same procedure was used at T1 (less than 5 months immersion) and T2 (T1+5 months).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors reported that implicit auditory processing is not correlated with explicit sound discrimination abilities or music memory. L2 prosody perception gain (they only included prosody perception because other task responses showed high ceiling effects (consonant) or didn't show significant gain (vowels)) correlated with music memory but not with implicit or explicit auditory processing. Multiple regressions showed similar effects, with music memory being the only significant predictor of L2 prosody perception gain. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors attributed the null findings partly to the experiencedness of the participant (immense English formal traning before coming to UK) and partly to the short time of the study (5 months only).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second study used similar design, but used different participants (who, at T1, had only come to UK for less than a month) and compared explicit processing with L2 pronunciation accuracy in spontanious speech. The results showed a main effect of time, and an interaction of time and explicit auditory processing with people that were more sensitive to formant became more accurate through time on segmentals, word stress, and also spoke faster with less pauses.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Overall I feel like the two studies didn't reach their hypothesis for they didn't have ideal participants. Ideally they should test people with less experience of the L2 so there will be more growth in their participants' L2 skills, but unfortunately they were only able to recruit students coming to the UK with extensive English training (ready to start their postgrad study, afterall). I also find it a little bit odd that by 'explicit auditory processing' and ‘domain general processing’ they meant sound discrimination thresholds (domain general?).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Saito, K., Sun, H., &amp; Tierney, A. (2020). Domain-general auditory processing determines success in second language pronunciation learning in adulthood: A longitudinal study.&nbsp;<em>Applied Psycholinguistics</em>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Sun, H., Saito, K., &amp; Tierney, A. (2020). A longitudinal investigation of explicit and implicit auditory processing in L2 segmental and suprasegmental acquisition.&nbsp;<em>Studies in Second Language Acquisition</em>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>209</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-02 13:20:02</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-02 05:20:02</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-02 13:46:35</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-02 05:46:35</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>2-jan-2021-sun-et-al-2020-saito-et-al-2020</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="eeg"><![CDATA[EEG]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="l2-speech-learning"><![CDATA[L2 speech learning]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="sla"><![CDATA[SLA]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="speech"><![CDATA[speech]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1609564807]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[52920736560]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[4 Jan 2021, Bosseler et al. (2013)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/04/4-jan-2021-bosseler-et-al-2013/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 13:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/04/4-jan-2021-bosseler-et-al-2013/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A MEG study that aims to test whether theta brain oscillation (previously shown to indicate attention) can reflect perceptual narrowing of speech. Three groups, 6-months, 12-months, and adults, participated the odd-ball paradigm study. Relative theta power was recorded in conditions varying in Frequency (frequently presented syllable vs. infrequent) and language (native vs. non-native). The authors hypothesized that 6-month-olds would show more RTP for Frequent vs. Infrequent, adult would show more RTP for Non-native vs. Native, while 12-months-olds would show transitional pattern closer to adults.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>All three predictions were confirmed by statistics. There was a significant interaction of age x frequency, with only 6-months-olds showing significantly more RTP for frequent vs. infrequent; there was also an interaction of age x language, with with effects of language in adults and 12-months-olds.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors concluded that the theta brain oscillation indexes an implicit learning process that entails a shift of attention to speech stimuli.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Bosseler, A., Taulu, S., Pihko, E., Mäkelä, J., Imada, T., Ahonen, A., &amp; Kuhl, P. (2013). Theta brain rhythms index perceptual narrowing in infant speech perception. <em>Frontiers in psychology</em>, <em>4</em>, 690.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>225</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-04 21:47:54</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-04 13:47:54</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-04 21:47:54</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-04 13:47:54</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>4-jan-2021-bosseler-et-al-2013</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="meg"><![CDATA[MEG]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="perceptual-narrowing"><![CDATA[perceptual narrowing]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="speech"><![CDATA[speech]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53008369076]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1609768084]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[6 Jan 2021, Friederici (2011)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/06/6-jan-2021-friederici-2011/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 08:41:12 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/06/6-jan-2021-friederici-2011/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is what I feel like the ultimate review of neural basis of language processing. I can’t believe this is published on a journal and not as a chapter of a book. The review is 30+ pages long and describes the language network, the processing (comprehension) network in particular, time course of auditory comprehension (from ERPs) and finally made an effort to combine the time evidence and space evidence in one model. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I feel like this is an article that’s very hard to write notes on, because the article itself is already written in a very clear and concise style, I feel that any attempts to write its summary or notes would be no more than paraphrasing. So I’ll just make a list of what this article covered, and the future me can go back to the original article for details.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The author first described the language network, involving the IFG (BA44, 45, 47) and the STG (I noticed that the temporoparietal portion of language network in this one is slightly different from other reviews, maybe because of the time of the review), as well as the two parallel dorsal pathways and two ventral pathways, arcuate fascicle from pSTG to premotor, superior longitudinal fascicle from pSTG to BA44, the extreme fiber capsule system EFCS from STG to BA45, the uncinate fascicle from STG to FOP. In this section the author also briefly reviewed functions of each area. This section also covered the default language network located in the perisylvian cortex, and stressed that experimental studies only represent a modulation of this default network.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The author then covered evidence of neural basis of each of the language processing steps. Starting from acoustic-phonological analysis which involves the PAC, planum temporale, planum polare, and STG; to initial syntax processing involving the FOP and the aSTG; computation of semantic and syntactic relations, where the author did some meta analytical work, and discussed in much detail the role of STG and IFG in this process. ←<strong> Note to self </strong>this is the core of the study and should read again when necessary. Finally, the author covered prosodic processing and stressed the right lateralization of intonation (supralingustic) processing.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In the next section, the author reviewed a bunch of ERP studies and established a language comprehension network, going through the N100, ELAN, LAN, N400, P600, the closure positive shift (CPS) in prosodic processes.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The final section includes a modeling of language processing that localized the ERPs in the language network, but also stressed some issues of such model, neuroanatomic variability, cross linguistic variability, and domain specificity. As well as some suggestions for future studies. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In fact, reading this article I was surprised that most information in it was not new to me, which I guess means that I’ve already learned a few things on the topic.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Friederici, A. D. (2011). The brain basis of language processing: from structure to function. <em>Physiological reviews</em>, <em>91</em>(4), 1357-1392.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>226</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-06 16:41:12</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-06 08:41:12</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-06 16:41:12</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-06 08:41:12</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>6-jan-2021-friederici-2011</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="fmri"><![CDATA[fMRI]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="max-planck"><![CDATA[Max Planck]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="processing"><![CDATA[processing]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="review"><![CDATA[review]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1609922480]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53080748188]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[7 Jan 2021, Boylan &amp; Pylkkänen (2016)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/07/7-jan-2021-boylan-pylkkanen-2016/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 08:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=234</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is an unpublished work I bumped into while surfing the internet. A simultaneous MEG and EEG study on localization of the N400 and the P600.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Classical N400 and P600 inducing experiment designs were used, with some materials directly taken from Kutas &amp; Hillyard 1980 and Osterhout &amp; Holcomb 1992, it seems. Participants looked at visually presented words one at a time on ISI 300ms and made grammatical judgments at the end of each sentence. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I'm unfamiliar with MEG so I couldn't tell whether they did good data analysis. From what I understood, they correlated MEG source difference waves with ERP difference waves using mixed effects models. Their results, bery briefly, indicate that the N400 ERP is correlated with sources from the posterior portion of the left temporal region, while the P600 ERP is correlated with sources from the anterior remporal region. However, although they found the MEG N400 and the N400 ERP were in the same direction (more activity with more N400), they found the MEG P600 and the P600 ERP in opposite direction (more activity when less P600 i.e. in the control condition). They mentioned that the MEG community has been talking about an insensitivity of MEG to the P600 (null results), and could indicate that the P600 has subcortical source. They discussed the opposite directioness of MEG data and ERP data on the P600, and finally reached a hypothesis that the P600 might partly reflect normal structure building rather than reanalysis. (←something about this confuses me, yes of course there are regular structure building in sentence comprehension, but can we say that the P600 *reflects* regular structure building? Does this wording mean regular structure building is *contributing* to the P600? That regular structure building increases the amplitude of P600? It seems very doubtful that this is true. But it sure seem possible to me that the 'ERP component for regular structure building' overlaps with 'the P600', but the former should be masking the later according to my intuition. I'm not sure what the authors of this paper is trying to say at the end, I think the most useful piece of information I got from this paper is that the P600 may be largely subcortical.)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Boylan, Christine. (2016). Lexical access vs. composition in the left temporal lobe: A simultaneous MEG and EEG study on N400 and P600 effects.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>234</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-07 16:33:05</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-07 08:33:05</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-07 16:33:05</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-07 08:33:05</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>7-jan-2021-boylan-pylkkanen-2016</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53122934444]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1610008390]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[8 Jan 2021, He et al. (2020)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/08/8-jan-2021-he-et-al-2020/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 08:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/08/8-jan-2021-he-et-al-2020/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A ERP study on cross modal priming effects on the N400. The study compared hand gestures seen from the front vs. the side and their effects on the N400.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Participants saw a priming video showing the communicative hand gestures (eg indicating a large object with hands opening up), before seeing visually presented sentences either congruent with the gesture or incongruent. The authors collected both EEG signals during gesture viewing and sentence viewing.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>From gesture viewing, they found that gestures seen from both the front and the side reduced alpha band (8-12hz) and beta band (16-24hz) oscillation power, but only the beta band showed more decrease with frontal viewed gesture vs. lateral viewed gesture with a right middle frontal localization. The alpha band decrease is previously associated with general sensory/motor perception, while the beta band decrease associated with fine-grained motor-related features. As for the N400, only frontal viewed gestures elicited significant N400 effect on the incongruent target word, while there were no significant N400 effect for the lateral viewed gestures. Amplitude differences also revealed a significant cluster where congruency effects and gesture position interacted, the cluster having a central-parietal distribution.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Overall, this study showed that cross-modal priming (gestures) can modulate the N400, moreover, view point of the gesture can play a role in the modulating effect.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>He, Y., Luell, S., Muralikrishnan, R., Straube, B., &amp; Nagels, A. (2020). Gesture's body orientation modulates the N400 for visual sentences primed by gestures. <em>Human brain mapping</em>, <em>41</em>(17), 4901-4911.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>238</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-08 16:36:24</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-08 08:36:24</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-08 16:36:24</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-08 08:36:24</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>8-jan-2021-he-et-al-2020</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="cross-modal-priming"><![CDATA[cross-modal priming]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="eeg"><![CDATA[EEG]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1610094993]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53165730714]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[9 Jan 2021, Brouwer et al. (2017)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/09/9-jan-2021-brouwer-et-al-2017/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 07:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=243</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A study that used recurrent neural network to simulate N400 and P600 amplitudes from a previous study, based on a Retrieval-Integration account, where the N400 reflects semantic retrieval and the P600 reflects integration of meaning (to context).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The introduction started by introducing the "semantic P600", where syntactically sound but semantically anomalous sentences ('The javelin threw the athletes.') elicited no N400 effect but a P600 effect. The paper introduced a single-stream account of the semantic P600 effects, that is, the N400 only reflects meaning retrieval (thus not affected by whether it was the javelin that threw the athletes or the athletes threw the javelin), while the P600 reflects a more general integration process (thus affected by whether the agent and the patient are plausible). The authors aimed to test this account by a recurrent neural network designed to simulate N400 and P600 amplitudes based on this account, and a successful simulation led the authors to confirm their theory. (Note that in this study, results from classical N400 studies like Kutas Hilliard 1980 are interpreted as having a biphasic N400+P600 effect).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The simple recurrent network had two modules, a Retrieval module and an Integration module, and in total consisted of five layers: input, retrieval, retrieval output, integration, and integration output. A hidden layer of integration context affects the retrieval and integration layer, and results from the integration layer also feed the integration context layer. Thus, the model will first take a word form, add contextual meaning to retrieve word meaning, then integrate this result with contextual meaning to have a final output of utterance representation (theta role assigned representations). At each layer, activation level of the artificial neurons is calculated. (There were a figure and a formula for the steps of the model and calculation of activation level).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The model was trained by materials similar to the study they were aiming to simulate, consisting of active and passive sentences of 6 or 7 words long (something like 'The [noun] [verbed] the [noun].'). Specifically they trained the model to know that in essence all nouns can be both agents or patients of any verb, but there are also some agent/patient pairs that are especially favored for each verb. They trained the model to 100% correctness, meaning that output vectors are always more similar to its target vector than to its target vector of any other item.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Finally, they linked the N400 amplitude to the degree of change that a word induces in the activity pattern of the retrieval layer, where the pattern is established after processing the previous word; and linked the P600 amplitude to the degree of change that a given word's meaning induces in the activity patter of the integration layer, also established after processing the previous word. In total, they did two simulations (using two sets of training material).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As they are using cosine similarity/dissimilarity, they z-scored their previous ERP results to compare with the model simulations.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The simulations successfully captured N400 patterns: no N400 effect in the role reversed condition 'Javelin threw athletes', and N400 effects in the mismatch conditions 'Cook sung meal', both in active voice and passive voice. The simulations also did a good job capturing P600 patterns, showing P600 effects in all three non-standard conditions. However, although the simulated effect size orders are consistent with actual ERP studies for the N40, with passive mismatch &gt; active mismatch &gt; active role reversal, the simulated P600 effect size orders are not entirely consistent: model predicted passive mismatch &gt; active mismatch &gt; active reversal, actual experiments showed a different pattern with active reversal &gt; active mismatch &gt; passive mismatch. However, the authors then made some corrections with their P600 ERP results, substracting preceding N400 effects from the P600 data, they got the same pattern as the simulations.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>(I suppose they used mismatches and role reversion on the verb position because the Dutch sentences they were using all ended with the verb (something like 'The cook had the meal prepared').)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I have to say that I comprehended the paper only thanks to my friend who has knowledge in machine learning. Apparently (ok rooky speaking time) a neural network in the machine learning senario can be seen as some formula with some undetermined parameters (and all networks that are called recurrent neural network share the same basis formula, ← which is a crucual piece of information that I didn't previously know so couldn't comprehend what exactly is happening when people train models), and training a model means to let the model process material using a random parameter setting, if this setting gives better results than the previous setting, then this is the new 'best setting' and is to be compared with the next process, and the procedure is repeated until a satisfactory parameter setting is reached. (My small brain always wonders why people that play with computers and people that play with human brains use very similar terminologies, which often leads to semantic competetion in my little brain when I try to learn new stuff.)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In the discussion section, the authors proposed that their model also predicts that, the N400 can be modulated by semantic feature overlap between the current word and the precious word (obviously, if we see the N400 as reflecting differences in semantic representations, and in this case it contains both independet word features and contextual features). They were able to say that in their simulations, the N400 difference is mainly elicited by context, because there weren't much semantic overlapping between their target words and their previous words. However this obviously doesn't mean that semantic overlapping *cannot* affect the N400. In fact, they refered to studies that showed N400 effects with two-word priming paradigm to stress the role of semantic feature overlapping. (But then they carried on to say that the N400 in the two-word priming studies should reflect semantic overlapping rather than contextual priming, which confuses me because I thought in a two-word situation, semantic overlap *is* the contextual priming, isn't it? (Like what else could the first word possibly prime the second word with?) I guess I would put the words this way: if, suppose we have two situations where there are identical supralinguistic context (like action scenes etc), this model would predict that the situation where the actual words have more semantic overlapping with the target word would elicit less N400 than the situation where the previous words share less overlapping features with the target word.)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Brouwer, Harm, et al. "A neurocomputational model of the N400 and the P600 in language processing." <em>Cognitive science</em> 41 (2017): 1318-1352.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>243</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-09 15:48:00</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-09 07:48:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-09 15:48:00</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-09 07:48:00</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>9-jan-2021-brouwer-et-al-2017</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="machine-learning"><![CDATA[machine learning]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="model-simulation"><![CDATA[model simulation]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="p600"><![CDATA[P600]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1610178485]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53206812952]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[10 Jan 2021, Grisoni et al. (2020)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/11/10-jan-2021-grisoni-et-al-2020/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 14:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=250</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A ERP study that directly correlated the recently found semantic prediction potential (SPP) with the N400. For stimuli the study used high constraint vs. low constraint spoken sentences with a animal vs. tool target word. They expected to see inverse correlated amplitudes of the SPP and N400.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The SPP, as they described, is a negative going component starting from -150ms from target onset (?). In this study, they had a 1100ms silent period between the previous word and the target word, so I suppose that also translates to about 1000ms from previous word onset? I wonder why they chose to describe the component relative to the target word rather than the previous word, it seems to me that the previous word is maybe a better reference point, since at the appearing of the SPP the target word didn't exist yet, after all. But this is a very minor question. The SPP, according to the authors, reflects predictive effort, since more constraining context (meaning more predictive target word) elicits a larger SPP vs. neutral context ('The German postoffice's logo is...a horn. vs. The company's logo is...a horn.), while the N400, according to the authors, should reflect error resolution.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Their results showed both the SPP and the N400 in all of the constraint conditions that correlate with cloze probability as well as corpus coocurrence frequency, and they did find a negative correlation between the two ERPs. In order to rule out the possibility that the correlation is only there because both are modulated by some other component, they also correlated amplitudes of the SPP to the N100, and found no significance. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>They also did localization analysis with the two ERPs, and found, form whole brain 0.005 uncorrected and ROI 0.05 corrected, that the ERPs has (additional?) activation in the frontal-central acivation for animal targets, and parietal-temporo-occipital activation for tool targets (the SPP activationg more parietal and the N400 activationg ventral occipital). They interpreted this finding as reflecting semantic category selectivity of said regions. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This paper is the first paper I read about the semantic prediction potential SPP, which, is only first reported by the same first author in 2016. Although I feel that it's still too new to be said robust, it does feel natural that previous studies didn't capture this component, since the 1000ms+ interval is quite long and the SPP only showing up at the very end of it. I don't recall reading any other paper taht has the same interval. I hope future studies can look more into this. I'm curious of the author's interpretation of the N400, though. They said that if the SPP is reflecting prediction itself, then the N400 can only reflect error resolution. This seems a little odd to me (just a little). It feels that 'the N400 doesn't reflect predicdtion itself' cannot entail that 'it reflects error resolution'. In the paper I read yesterday (Brouwer 2017), the N400 is described as reflecting meaning retrieval, and I think the retrieval interpretation goes well to with the SPP. Though, again, I don't feel that the two interpretation of the N400 are that conflicting, because I feel that, the error resolution processing in these situations may largely overlap with sementic retrieval (find out prediction is wrong - heard the new word - deal with/retrieve the new word).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Grisoni, L., Miller, T. M., &amp; Pulvermüller, F. (2017). Neural correlates of semantic prediction and resolution in sentence processing.&nbsp;<em>Journal of Neuroscience</em>,&nbsp;<em>37</em>(18), 4848-4858.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Grisoni, L., Tomasello, R., &amp; Pulvermüller, F. (2020). Correlated Brain Indexes of Semantic Prediction and Prediction Error: Brain Localization and Category Specificity.&nbsp;<em>Cerebral Cortex</em>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Luigi Grisoni, Felix R. Dreyer, Friedemann Pulvermüller, Somatotopic Semantic Priming and Prediction in the Motor System,&nbsp;<em>Cerebral Cortex</em>, Volume 26, Issue 5, May 2016, Pages 2353–2366,&nbsp;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhw026">https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhw026</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>250</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-11 22:22:38</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-11 14:22:38</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-11 22:33:40</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-11 14:33:40</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>10-jan-2021-grisoni-et-al-2020</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="eeg"><![CDATA[EEG]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="prediction"><![CDATA[prediction]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="spp"><![CDATA[SPP]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53299409355]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1610374962]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[13 Jan 2021, Kutas &amp; Federmeier (2011)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/13/13-jan-2021-kutas-federmeier-2011/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 06:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=261</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A review of the N400. Detailedly summarizes its discovery, characterization, and use. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Discovery</strong>. ERPs were discovered in the 1950s. In 1980, Kutas &amp; Hillyard adapted the oddball paradigm in trying to elicit a language P3b, but found the N400 instead. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Characteristics</strong>. The N400's latency is rarely affected by any factors, while it's <strong>amplitude</strong> is most susceptible to manipulation. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Use.</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Early</strong>. Studies successively found that the N400 is <strong><em>insensitive</em></strong> to <strong>unexpected stress/intonation</strong>, or <strong>simple grammatical violation</strong>. It's found that all words elicit an N400, whose amplitude correlates with <strong>cloze probablility</strong>, regardless of context constraint. Semantic anomalies was neither necessary nor sufficient for the N400. The N400 is also found to be <strong><em>insensitive</em></strong> to <strong>affirmation/negation</strong> sentences' meaning or truth value, only sensitive to the semantic relationship between the words (N400 in 'A bird is not a vehicle'.) Later, non-sentence <strong>word lists</strong> are also found to elicit the N400. N400 is also found to be cross-modal, with <strong>spoken, written words, sign languages, images, and faces</strong> when primed (in this paper the authors denied music N400s, but from what I read earlier (Calma-Roddin Drury 2020) there is a N400-like effect with music).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The N400 made some major contributions to psycholinguistics, providing evidence that language comprehension/processing has immediacy and incrementality. Every word in the sentence elicits an N400. Many debates took place concerning on which level of processing the N400 is. Apparently, there were pre-lexical and post-lexical theories, but both couldn't explain some features of the N400, with lexical relevence and context eliciting similar N400 effect, but higher-level context overshadowing lexical relevence when both present. The paper settled down on a lexical theory, that the N400 reflect processing on the lexical assess level. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Supralinguistic</strong>. The N400 is found with <strong>discourse</strong> (contexts more than one sentence), <strong>world knowledge</strong> violations, and <strong>figurative language</strong> (jokes and metaphors). N400 studies on metaphors suggest metaphor is processed quantitatively rather than qualitaticely, with largest N400 for metaphor ('power is an intoxicant') and medium N400 for words requiring explicit mapping ('cough syrup is an intoxicant'). Gestures, although the authors caracterized as non-linguistic, also modulates the semantic N400 when seen together with sentences.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Non-linguistic</strong>. The N400 is found with <strong>picture</strong> sequences, familiar <strong>scenes</strong>, videos of <strong>everyday events</strong>, as well as with <strong>math</strong>. The N400 also helped in dessociation of recollection effect and familiarity effect in <strong>memory</strong> (though called the frontal N400, some say they are the same). The morphology , timing, and topography of these N400s didn't differ with language N400s, suggesting a view that the N400 reflects meaning access in a broader sense.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>The P600</strong>. Studies have found that many implausible language ('For breakfast the eggs would only eat...') doesn't elicit the N400, but elicit the P600 instead.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Prediction</strong>. Apart from the classical prediction N400 studies, the paper also stressed that predictable vs. unpredictable words diverges prior to a word's recognition point and occurs as soon as 'something felt wrong'. Studies in aging suggests that prediction shifts toward more passive, bottom-up strategies in many aging cases. As for brain source of prediction, the paper stressed a left lateralization with some level of involvement of the RH.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Word recognition</strong>. The N400 helped establish a interactive view of word recognitijon, suggesting that lexical categorizing and orthographic processing happens in parallel with attempts at meaning access. However the authors pointed out that this seems to contradicting some eye-moving theories with fixation and saccade planning driven by word recognition (←but is this still the newest theory???)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Acquisition and bilingualism</strong>. In children, the N400 is detectable at 9 months with action sequences, 12 months with picture/word congruency, 19 months with semantic congruency, and 30 months with prediction. In adults, the N400 amplitude reductions is found to be detective only after tens of hours of new language training. In SLA, the N400 is found to correlate with proficiency and AOA.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Localization</strong>. With help form intracranial recording and MEG, the N400 is shown to be a wave of activity, starting 250ms in left pSTG, spreading forwangd and ventrally to left temporal lobe 350ms, then to right ATL and bilateral frontal up to 500ms.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Task</strong>. The N400 can be modulated by task demands, attention, and masking, with more attention to stimuli eliciting more N400 amplitude. However, the N400 doesn't dissapear without attention, suggesting a level of automatic semantic processing. The N400 is also detectable in sleep and amnesia. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Special population</strong>. The N400 is used to measure lexical abilities in certain populations with Alzheimer's, aphasia, autism, etc. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Overall I think this is a very detailed review providing a whole picture of the N400 upto 2011. I certainly need to come back to its very rich references if I'm to do anything with the N400.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Kutas, M., &amp; Federmeier, K. D. (2011). Thirty years and counting: finding meaning in the N400 component of the event-related brain potential (ERP).&nbsp;<em>Annual review of psychology</em>,&nbsp;<em>62</em>, 621-647.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>261</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-13 14:04:46</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-13 06:04:46</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-13 14:05:50</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-13 06:05:50</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>13-jan-2021-kutas-federmeier-2011</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="eeg"><![CDATA[EEG]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="review"><![CDATA[review]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53372188405]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1610517890]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[13 Jan 2021, Sakai et al. (2006)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/13/13-jan-2021-sakai-et-al-2006/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 06:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=271</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A Japanese study I bumped into when reading Kutas Ferdemeier 2011. The study is about Japanese calssifiers and the N400. A simple N400 study comparing congrugent and incongrugent classifiers appearing before a noun. They had similar results as Kwon et al 2017 on Chinese classifier, but they only had correct vs. incorrect, while Kwon also had a 'correct but unusual' condition. Unfortunately, this study gave an odd task to the participants: to make dicisions on whether the classifier in the sentence is compatible with the noun, which is a task that explicitly directed the participant's attention to the target. Their results showed very large N400 effects, which the authors attributed to some other random factors but I think the too-obvious N400 is all about the explicit task.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Sakai, Y. (2006). An ERP study of the integration process between a noun and a numeral classifier: Semantic or morpho-syntactic?. <em>Cognitive Studies</em>, <em>13</em>(3), 443-454.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Kwon, N., Sturt, P., &amp; Liu, P. (2017). Predicting semantic features in Chinese: Evidence from ERPs. <em>Cognition</em>, <em>166</em>, 433-446.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>271</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-13 14:19:28</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-13 06:19:28</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-13 14:19:56</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-13 06:19:56</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>13-jan-2021-sakai-et-al-2006</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="classifier"><![CDATA[classifier]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="eeg"><![CDATA[EEG]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="japanese"><![CDATA[Japanese]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53372571797]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1610518772]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[14 Jan 2021, Delogu et al. (2019)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/14/14-jan-2021-delogu-et-al-2019/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 04:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=277</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A ERP study aiming at providing evidence for the Retrieval-Integration account of the N400 and the P600's functional role (Brouwer et al. 2017).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The study used two-sentence pairs as stimuli. The first sentence providing context, while the second sentence is grammatically unambiguous with a target word that either is consistant/inconsistant/irrelevant with the context. All manipulations were made in the context sentence.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>consistant (baseline): John <strong>entered</strong> the restaurant. Before long, he opened the <span style="text-decoration:underline;">menu</span>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>inconsistant (event related violation): John<strong> left</strong> the restarurant. Before long, he opened the <span style="text-decoration:underline;">menu</span>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>irrelevant (event unrelated violation): John entered the<strong> apartment</strong>. Before long, he opened the <span style="text-decoration:underline;">menu</span>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors predicted that, with the retrieval-integration view, they should see N400 effect in the irrelevant condition but not in the inconsistant condition, (because 'restaurant' would preactivate 'menu' regardless of leaving or entering), and see P600 effects in the last two conditions. (The traditional semantic integration - syntactic reanalysis view would predict N400 in last two conditions and no P600 effects).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As a result, N400 effects were only shown in the irrelevant condition, supporting the predictions. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>However, the study reported P600 effects only in the inconsistant condition but not the irrelevant condition. This seems to contradict both the integration view and the syntactic reanalysis view of the P600. The author tried to explain this pattern with task dependency, individual difference, but in the end settled with a component overlap explanation, as they argued a larger N400 effect in the irrelevent condition that could mask the successive P600 amplitude.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Delogu, F., Brouwer, H., &amp; Crocker, M. W. (2019). Event-related potentials index lexical retrieval (N400) and integration (P600) during language comprehension. <em>Brain and cognition</em>, <em>135</em>, 103569.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>277</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-14 12:27:47</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-14 04:27:47</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-14 12:27:47</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-14 04:27:47</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>14-jan-2021-delogu-et-al-2019</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="eeg"><![CDATA[EEG]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="p600"><![CDATA[P600]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="retrieval-integration"><![CDATA[retrieval-integration]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1610598472]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53415793094]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[23 Jan 2021, Delaney-Busch et al. 2019]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/23/23-jan-2021-delaney-busch-et-al-2019/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 13:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/23/23-jan-2021-delaney-busch-et-al-2019/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A study that fitted a Bayesian learning model to ERP data to study trial-by-trial N400 modulation in two-word priming settings.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The ERP study had two blocks, in block 1 10% of the target word were related with the prime word, while in block 2 50% of the words were related.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The model assumed that the participant estimates the chance of seeing a related word based on both Forward Association Strength and environmental confidence (how likely the participant believes the trial will be related words), plus a small chance of encountering the target word as an unrelated random word. They log transformed the output to indicate surprisal (?)</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>They initially got highly significant results doing regressions of the model output and actual ERP data, but they feared that the significance can be largely evoked by the raw semantic priming effect. They entered categorical relatedness as control predictor in their mixed effects regression, variance accounted for dropped a little but was still significant. However they still feared that multicollinearity between categorical relatedness and the model output could be a factor. So they did additional regressions controlling for categorical relatedness, trial-by-trial frequency, and FAS, the results became less strong but was still significant (β-2.3 t-2.11 p0.03).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>They then computed likelihood with different precision parameter (how quickly/largely the agent changes their confidence based on the newest trial: from no change at all to completely flip their belief). And they found that υ=77 is the best fit (min1 max800). Which indicates real participants begin to give more weight to data in block2 than block1 around 77th trial (block 1 had 400 trials).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>They also compared log-transformed probability (surprisal) with raw probability (?), and found that surprisal but not probability accounted for variance in N400 amplitudes (??).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Overall I think they provided a working model of trial-by-trial adaptations on the N400. They also stressed that their model assuming the agent updating their belief on each trial may be just a simple way to look at things, and said the comprehender maybe could keep track of multiple sets of beliefs about the environmental statistics and is able to switch or adjust from model to model.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reference</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Delaney-Busch, N., Morgan, E., Lau, E., &amp; Kuperberg, G. R. (2019). Neural evidence for Bayesian trial-by-trial adaptation on the N400 during semantic priming. <em>Cognition</em>, <em>187</em>, 10-20.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>290</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-23 21:41:28</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-23 13:41:28</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-23 21:41:28</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-23 13:41:28</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>23-jan-2021-delaney-busch-et-al-2019</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="adaptations"><![CDATA[adaptations]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="model-simulation"><![CDATA[model simulation]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1611409301]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53806834430]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[26 Jan 2021, Tiedt et al. (2020)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/26/26-jan-2021-tiedt-et-al-2020/</link>
  <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 14:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/01/26/26-jan-2021-tiedt-et-al-2020/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A study of N400 modulation in the aging population.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Using a two word priming paradigm the study compared RT of lexical decision and the N400 to study the effect of aging on lexical processing.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>They found a dissociation between RT and the N400: while the elderly showed increased priming effects in RT (similar RT as younger for related word pair, increased RT for unrelated word pair); they also showed decreased N400 effects.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors pointed out that their results are consistent with both RT literature and N400 literature. However, the increased priming effect in RT is often interpreted as the elderly being more aided by lexical context, while the decrease in N400 effects is taken to reflect less access to lexical context in processing, contradictory to the RT interpretation. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In the discussion section, the authors noted that a. The increased priming effect is reflected not in a faster recognition of related words, but in a slower recognition of unrelated words; b. The N400 is not only subject to semantic relatedness, since phonetic neighborhood etc can also show the n400 effect. Based on these they established an explanation for their results: that the RT results reflect a greater need of context in the elderly in lexical processing, and the diminished N400 effect doesn’t necessarily indicate impaired access to context, but could reflect age-related changes in resource allocation (as shown in imaging studies that the elderly have more interhemispheric activations). They concluded their results to show preserved context sensibility but higher lexical processing cost.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reference </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Tiedt, H. O., Ehlen, F., &amp; Klostermann, F. (2020). Age-related dissociation of N400 effect and lexical priming. <em>Scientific Reports</em>, <em>10</em>(1), 1-10.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>292</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-01-26 22:47:32</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-01-26 14:47:32</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-01-26 22:47:32</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-01-26 14:47:32</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>26-jan-2021-tiedt-et-al-2020</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="aging"><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1611672461]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53928831457]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[20 Feb 2021, Bouton et al. (2020)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/02/20/20-feb-2021-bouton-et-al-2020/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 06:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=298</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A study using behavioral and MEG to study neural activities underlying audio visual integration, in the cases of fusion and combination. Fusion and combination refer to situations where incongruent audio and visual (face) stimuli elicit either a fused or mixed perception of the sound (auditory /aba/ + visual /aga/ = perceptual/ada/; auditory /aga/ + visual /aba/ = perceptual/agba/). Perceptual fusion and combination are called the "McGurk effect". The authors hypothesized that while fusion is a more straight foward solution facing incongruent audio visual input, combination only happens when perceptual fusion fails, and elicits additional activity in the IFG.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The first experiment involved a repetition task where participants were showed inconsistant audio and lip movement, and were required to repeat whe they heared as quickly as possible. The authors analysed RT in realtion with conditions. (Stimuli in each experimental condition are designed to elicit either fusion or combination perception, based on previous study results. F2 and lip aperture are used to construct a two dimensional feature space, which can predict perceptual fusion vs. combination. eg, /ada/ has similar F2 to /aba/ and lip aperture to /aga/, thus a fusion; but no sound had F2 of /aga/ plus lip aperture of /aba/, thus a combination of /agba/. Only trials where participants did respond with the expected response were included in analysis, same is true for all experiments in this study). Results suggested that combination is slower than both fusion and control (congruent), and no difference in RT between fusion and congruent. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second experiment involved a decision task, where a printed syllable preceded the audio-face stimuli, and the participant's task is to decide whether the audio-face coresponded with the printed letters. This experiment confirmed results from the first experiment, and also helped rule out the effect of articulation planning of combined consonants like /agba/.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then, the authors carried out an MEG study where participants were showed the audio-face stimuli and were asked to choose what they heard among 5 alternatives (audio, visual, fusion/ada/, combination1/agba/, combination2/abga/). The audio-face stimuli in this experiment varies in stimulus onset asychronies from -120ms audio lead to 40ms audio lag. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>From the MEG experiment, the authors drew several results, supported by a range of simple to carefully modeled statictic tests. They found enhanced neural activity in the STS and IFG in combination. They also found enhanced connectivity form and to the IFG in combination through out the experimental trial. Further, they used a general linear model of 6 rois to study time sensitivity and neural determinants of combination and fusion. The glm suggests that incongruence is first processed in the STS, and the audio visual asynchrony is first processed in the IFG. Decoding analysis showed that univariate classification was possible in the STS for conbination vs. congruent, combination vs fusion, and congruent vs fusion, but was possible in the IFG only for combination vs congrent. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>All in all, the authors pictured a model where combination results both from the identification of the incongruence between the auditory and visual features in the STS, and from the detection of fine audio visual asynchronies in the IFG. Fusion and combination arise from a visual pre-activation of the STS followed by the tracking of the asynchrony in the IFG, which is either interrupted by the input of a compativle audio (fusion), or sequentially continued by the input of an incompativle audio (combination). Combination is triggered by a failure of fusion in the STS.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This study actually gave me some idea of how to intepret some of the results I had from a perceptual judgement task. I was quite busy the previous days applying for stuff, learning statistics, and enjoying holidays(?), so I was delighted to read a immediately useful article the first day I'm returning to this blog.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reference</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Bouton, S., Delgado-Saa, J., Olasagasti, I., &amp; Giraud, A. L. (2020). Audio-visual combination of syllables involves time-sensitive dynamics following from fusion failure. <em>Scientific reports</em>, <em>10</em>(1), 1-18.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>298</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-02-20 14:18:51</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-02-20 06:18:51</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-02-20 14:18:51</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-02-20 06:18:51</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>20-feb-2021-bouton-et-al-2020</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="audio-visual-integration"><![CDATA[audio-visual integration]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="meg"><![CDATA[MEG]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[55030939477]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1613801936]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[21 Feb 2021, Du et al. (2020)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/02/21/21-feb-2021-du-et-al-2020/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 04:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=302</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>An N400 study on effects of background music on sentence comprehension. The study compared N400 amplitudes elicited by world knowledge inconsistant vs. consistant senteces in background silence vs. high-arousal (fast tempo) music vs. low-arousal (slow-tempo) music. The experimenters also recorded participants' self-reported arousal level during the experiment. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Both high- and low-arousal music pieces are selected from major mode orchestral music without lyrics. The self-reported arousal level did not differ with music type.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The major discovery of this study is that N400 amplitude is higher when background music is present than in silence. However, N400 amplitude did not differ with music type in this study. Since the self-reported arousal level also did not differ with music type, the effect of music type on N400 amplitude may need further study. The N400 differece between silence and bgm was associated with sentence integration difficulty caused by limited attentive resources when there's bgm to be processed too. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>However I feel that this intepretation is not the typical intepretation of differences in N400 amplitude. It's resonable to intepret N400 amplitude increase by processing difficulty, but attention is not typically associated with N400 amplitude changes (according to Kutas and Federmeier, at least). So I feel that maybe there is some other intepretation for N400 changes saw in this study.  On a second thought, I haven't read many studies that looked at N400 modulation by another factor, if that makes sense. The N400 studies I've read all seem to manipulate the sementic anomaly in some ways, (whether they talk about masking or priming, the manipulation is always supposed to affect semantic processing "directly"), but the presence of bgm probably isn't supposed to affect semantic processing in the same way as prime words. I did find a study that looked at priming effect of music, though, e.g. major mode chore + sad word elicited a (slightly) higher N400 at the word than mojor mode chore + happy word. For now I can't think of other valid intepretations of this study, but I do wonder whether the silence vs. bgm did something to the N400 by themselves. Suppose each stimulus elicits an N400, shouldn't we expect any sound to increase the N400 amplitude than mere silence?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reference</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Du, M., Jiang, J., Li, Z., Man, D., &amp; Jiang, C. (2020). The effects of background music on neural responses during reading comprehension. <em>Scientific Reports</em>, <em>10</em>(1), 1-10.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Steinbeis, N., &amp; Koelsch, S. (2011). Affective priming effects of musical sounds on the processing of word meaning. <em>Journal of cognitive neuroscience</em>, <em>23</em>(3), 604-621.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>302</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-02-21 12:57:03</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-02-21 04:57:03</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-02-21 12:57:03</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-02-21 04:57:03</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>21-feb-2021-du-et-al-2020</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="eeg"><![CDATA[EEG]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[55066078218]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1613883427]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[25 Feb 2021, Chen et al. (2019)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/02/25/25-feb-2021-chen-et-al-2019/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 04:48:36 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=309</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A study using data from the Human Connetome Project (n=313) to investigate fonctional &amp; structural connectivities of the VWFA in the whole brain context.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The study mainly demostrated that the VWFA has strong connectivity with the frontal-parietal attention network, including the intraparietal sulcus IPS, V5/middle temporal visual area MT+ fromtal eye fields FEF.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Whole brain structural connectivity was analysed using probabilistic tractography, and indentified the inferior longitudinal fasciculus ILF, superior longitudinal fasciculus SLF, and the ventral occipital fasciculus/temporal-parietal-superior parietal lobule vOF/TP-SPL as main white-matter tracts associated with the VWFA. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>ROI structural connectivity analysis revealed connectivity between VWFA and the ITG, mSTS, and ATL as the language network; as well as with FEF, MT+, aIPS, and pIPS as the attention network. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Functional connectivity analysis showed moderate connectivity of VWFA with nodes of the language network, but revealed a striking pattern of connectivity between VWFA snd attention network nodes, especially with MT+ and IPS. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This study also did multiple regressions to study whether VWFA connectivity to language or attention predict standard scores of language or visual attention abilities (word reading and picture vocabulary, Flanker's test). They found a double dissociation in which cocnnectivity between VWFA and language network predicted language performance uniquely, and VWFA with attention network predicted visuo-spatial attention uniquely. They also found that both structual + functional connectivity measures better predicted both behavioral measures than just structural or just functional connectivity. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Overall, this study critisized previous studies of the VWFA of using small sample size, and doing a priori tests and analysis associating the VWFA and language networks. The authors did not deny the involvement of VWFA in language, but emphasized the function of VWFA in visual attention.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reference</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Chen, L., Wassermann, D., Abrams, D. A., Kochalka, J., Gallardo-Diez, G., &amp; Menon, V. (2019). The visual word form area (VWFA) is part of both language and attention circuitry. <em>Nature communications</em>, <em>10</em>(1), 1-12.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>309</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-02-25 12:48:36</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-02-25 04:48:36</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-02-25 12:48:36</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-02-25 04:48:36</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>25-feb-2021-chen-et-al-2019</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="attention"><![CDATA[attention]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="dwi"><![CDATA[DWI]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="fmri"><![CDATA[fMRI]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="vwfa"><![CDATA[VWFA]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[55236228072]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1614228522]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[05 March 2021, thoughts]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/03/05/05-march-2021-thoughts/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 07:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=323</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Ok this sounds like excuses (maybe it is(). Apparently I'm not writing the notes as regularly as the last few months. One reason is that since I'm feeling healthier, I started to work on my project again. So when I was dedicating myself to data analysis (and learning data analysis, unfortunately(), sometimes I couldn't bring myself to read (bad habit, though!). Another reason is that I'm not writing notes to every article that I read, now that I'm trying to focus on specific topics and go deeper, sometimes there just seems to be very little to write about the article of the day. I certainly hope that this little blog goes on! So this is also a reminder to self that I should post more often. I've just printed more articles out (I used to be a full-time e-reader, but recently I feel that my eye sights have gone considerably worse, so sorry environment but I need to switch to less eye-destroying habits), and hopefully I'll find many things to write about them.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>323</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-03-05 15:17:22</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-03-05 07:17:22</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-03-05 15:17:22</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-03-05 07:17:22</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>05-march-2021-thoughts</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[55566448595]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1614928646]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[12 March 2021, Pulvermüller &amp; Grisoni (2020)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/03/12/12-march-2021-pulvermuller-grisoni-2020/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 03:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=329</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A very interesting brief introduction? review? of the novel prediction potential (PP), a slow negative-going potential shift preceding predictable (predicted?) stimuli.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors briefly reviewed the N400 and argued that the N400 shouldn't be an ideal index of prediction (which is supposed to happen before the onset of the critical word). Instead, citing recent experimental studies, they proposed that there is a negative-going potential shift that can be observed starting from several hundred ms before the critical word onset. The studies they cited used a range of stimuli types (spoken/written words, words-action sounds, etc.). I noticed that these studies generally had a longer gap between the previous word and the target word (for example 1s), presumably in order to separate prediction elicited activities and processing of the target word. The authors further argued against the hypothesis that the prediction potential is the result of attention or arousal, stating that the PP is observable when subjects are instructed to move their attention away from stimuli.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>My question to this article is that, it seems that so far the prediction potential can only be observed in the "context constraining" condition. In the classic N400 literature there seems to be a distinction between context constraint and cloze probability, such that both high constraint and low constraint sentences can have low cloze probability (but plausible) endings, and the N400 only follows the cloze probability but not contextual constraint. Obviously, this contrast cannot be tested with the prediction potential paradigm (because the participant has no way of knowing the target word!), but I wonder whether this contrast means anything concerning the relation of this newfound potential and the N400. Maybe it would be interesting to have a study that looks at both potentials at the same time while trying to make the context vs. cloze distinction.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reference</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Pulvermüller, F., &amp; Grisoni, L. (2020). Semantic prediction in brain and mind. <em>Trends in Cognitive Sciences</em>, <em>24</em>(10), 781-784.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>329</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-03-12 11:37:35</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-03-12 03:37:35</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-03-12 11:37:35</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-03-12 03:37:35</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>12-march-2021-pulvermuller-grisoni-2020</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="eeg"><![CDATA[EEG]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="prediction-potential"><![CDATA[prediction potential]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1615520261]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[55835768465]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[17 March 2021, Lau et al. (2013)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/03/17/17-march-2021-lau-et-al-2013/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 05:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=337</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>An N400 study comparing strong predictive priming and low predictive priming (single word).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Stimuli were prime-target word pairs that are either semantically related or unrelated. High vs. low predictive context were realised by manipulating the proposion of related pairs in the experimental block. The high predictive block contained 40 related target, 40 unrelated target, 120 unrelated filler, and 160 related filler; the low predictive block contained the same amont of exp stimuli, and 280 unrelated filler. Task was to press a botton when identified an animal word, 40 animal word pairs (not included in exp items) were in each block. The low predictive block was always presented first. SOA was 600 ms.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>ERP results showed an effect of "predictability" on N400 amplitude, such that N400 effect was larger in the high predictable block (unrelated, low - related, low &lt; unrelated, high - related, high; and unrelated, low = unrelated, high; related, low &gt;&gt; related, high). Analyses also showed effect of prediction on N400 distribution, such that where was an interaction between hamisphere and anteriority (N400 effect largest across right posterior electrodes) only in high predictive blocks. They also found effects of prediction on N400 onset latency, such that high predictive block had an earlier-beginning N400 effect. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Personally, I think the results of this study are valid, but I'm not sure whether their design is representing and only representing "predictability", because I haven't seen any other studies  manipulating the proportion of related items as manipulating prediction.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reference</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Lau, E. F., Holcomb, P. J., &amp; Kuperberg, G. R. (2013). Dissociating N400 effects of prediction from association in single-word contexts. <em>Journal of cognitive neuroscience</em>, <em>25</em>(3), 484-502.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>337</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-03-17 13:56:07</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-03-17 05:56:07</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-03-17 13:56:07</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-03-17 05:56:07</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>17-march-2021-lau-et-al-2013</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[56035240815]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1615960572]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[18 March 2021, Hoeks and Brouwer (2014)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/03/18/18-march-2021-hoeks-and-brouwer-2014/</link>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 11:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=349</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A chapter of the Oxford handbook of language and social psychology, about potential usage of ERPs (N400 and P600) in the study of active communication.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The chapter introduced the dialogue immersion paradigm, where the participant is given a script of conversation, and is made believe to talk to an actual intellector, while the 'intellector' is pre-recorded (allowing for ERP time lock). (I guess they give the scripte to the subject and tell them they are supposed to do a little act??) The authors argued that this is a way to introduce some 'sense of involvement', to approach real life active conversation, while having some control over the stimuli and the data. However, the experiment using the dialogue immersion paradigm was never really published? I only found a manuscript of an undergrad thesis on researchgate. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>References</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hoeks, J. C., Brouwer, H., &amp; Holtgraves, T. (2014). Electrophysiological research on conversation and discourse. <em>The Oxford handbook of language and social psychology</em>, 365-386.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>349</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-03-18 19:12:07</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-03-18 11:12:07</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-03-18 19:12:07</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-03-18 11:12:07</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>18-march-2021-hoeks-and-brouwer-2014</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[56085489399]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1616065931]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[20 March 2021, Sitnikova et al. (2008)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/03/20/20-march-2021-sitnikova-et-al-2008/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 02:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/03/20/20-march-2021-sitnikova-et-al-2008/</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>An N400-P600 study that looked at real world events. Silent movies containing a context scene and a target scene was used (taking a chopping board and a loaf of bread - cut bread with bread knife (congruous); cut bread with electric iron (incongruous); iron shirt (unrelated)).</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There was a P600 like effect with incongruous vs. congruous, and an anterior N400 like effect with unrelated vs. congruous. What’s the most interesting to me is that the two effects were seemingly dissociable in this study, with incongruous - congruous showing little N400 effects and so on.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The authors discussed their findings under the semantic integration account of the N400, but maybe the newer retrieval account could have allowed them a more simple discussion.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Reference</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Sitnikova, T., Holcomb, P. J., Kiyonaga, K. A., &amp; Kuperberg, G. R. (2008). Two neurocognitive mechanisms of semantic integration during the comprehension of visual real-world events. <em>Journal of cognitive neuroscience</em>, <em>20</em>(11), 2037-2057.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>356</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-03-20 10:31:26</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-03-20 02:31:26</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-03-20 10:31:26</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-03-20 02:31:26</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>20-march-2021-sitnikova-et-al-2008</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="erp"><![CDATA[ERP]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="n400"><![CDATA[N400]]></category>
  <category domain="post_tag" nicename="p600"><![CDATA[P600]]></category>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1616207496]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[56153446225]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[18 April 2021, thoughts &amp; Perfors et al. (2010)]]></title>
  <link>https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/2021/04/18/18-april-2021-thoughts-perfors-et-al-2010/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 05:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>balalahelo</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">https://yilinghuo.wordpress.com/?p=359</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This article introduces the Bayesian learning model. I'm not particularly familiar with developmental cognitive science, but this article surprisingly gave me some intuitive examples of things I didn't understand about Bayesian stats, especially about the basic concepts, priors and what they represent. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I've been doing a few things recently. First is learning stats (and how to talk about math in English in general). My project with my supervisor is also progressing, and I'm starting to do some writing. I thought I would be pretty bad at it since I haven't been writing for a long time, but thanks to all the reading I've been doing it's actually reasonably smooth. I'm also trying to do some part time job to help myself financially. I didn't get the scholarship (again), but "luckily" my tuitions can be considered paid for (sigh). Rumors are that by September schools will be open, so if I can't choose the remote option I have to figure out something to pay for my living costs.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Perfors, A., Tenenbaum, J. B., Griffiths, T. L., &amp; Xu, F. (2011). A tutorial introduction to Bayesian models of cognitive development. <em>Cognition</em>, <em>120</em>(3), 302-321.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>359</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2021-04-18 13:13:37</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2021-04-18 05:13:37</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2021-04-18 13:13:37</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2021-04-18 05:13:37</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>18-april-2021-thoughts-perfors-et-al-2010</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="%e6%9c%aa%e5%88%86%e7%b1%bb"><![CDATA[未分类]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_last_editor_used_jetpack</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1618722821]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[57293376470]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>
  </channel>
</rss>
